### **VIVEK KUMAR RAI**

+91 8800 229466 - vivekraikumar23@gmail.com

### About me

I have extensive experience in designing for mobile app UI as per guidelines, especially Google's Android Material Design. I'm also an expert in designing icons and working in vector designs in Adobe Illustrator. I also have hands on experience in editing videos, using Adobe Premiere.

I'm a very quick learner and extremely committed to the quality of work I do. I started my career by doing basic graphics designing and now I'm an integral part of a multinational company making products for global users. Quite proud to say those are my designs.

I'm looking forward for better opportunities and challenges so that in a way it is mutually beneficial to myself and my employer and allow for future growth and advancement

#### Tools:

- ADOBE ILLUSTRATOR
- ADOBE PHOTOSHOP
- ADOBE PREMIERE
- ADOBE LIGHTROOM
- CORAL DRAW
- DREAMWEAVER
- FLASH, PAGE MAKER

# **Experience**

**Company:** SliQBits Private Limited (February 2015 to till date)

Designation: Graphics & Mobile UI Designer

SliQBits makes the best in class video streaming applications, one-way and two-way like SliQ and SliQLive.

#### Role:

- Design UI for new mobile app products.
- Continuously improve the present UI of various mobile apps.

- Make ads for Coca Cola, Airtel, OLX, VodaPhone, Dairy Milk, KitKat, Nescafe, Micromax, etc
- Involved in product design discussions and decision making.
- Involved in product use case discussions.
- Responsible for hiring product representatives.
- Responsible for conducting Table Tennis tournaments.

Company: Monsoon Multimedia Private Limited (January 2010 to February 2015)

**Designation:** Graphics Designer and Video Editor

Monsoon Multimedia was world's second best company in streaming video over internet from an STB.

#### Role:

- Design UI for 100's of remote controls with 3D effect and 4 different states.
- Design UI for PC software applications (for Vulkano, Flash, etc)
- Video editing for online shortened movie (10mm) format. (edit movie any movie length to 10 mins)
- Bollywicket UI designing.
- Software remote control testing.

Company: Inventa Cleantec Private Limited (August 2009 to January 2010)

**Designation:** Graphics Designer

Inventa makes various machines for cleaning metros, roads, etc in industrial level.

#### Role:

- Design machine catalogs for various electronic devices like Vacuum cleaners, manual sweepers etc.
- Design logos, machine design collages and other graphics.
- Any other work using Corel draw and Photoshop and Flash.

## **Education**

- One Year Diploma in "web designing" from (F-TEC) Noida
- B.A pass from PG Government College Tendon University
- 12<sup>th</sup> pass out from UP Board from M.R.D inter collage
- 10<sup>th</sup> pass out from UP Board from R.S.S Inter School.

## **Personal details**

Vivek kumar Rai, Single, Male, 27 Yrs.

Thank you.